这不公平 你说了让我去的
It's so unfair. You told me I could go.
我说的是
I told you you could go if you
你历史课要拿到"良"才能去 可你没拿到
got a B on your History exam, which you didn't.
我有学习功能障碍
I have a learning disability.
课文的字母像是会跑会跳
The letters jump around on the page
而且还颠三倒四的
and appear backwards.
宝贝 咱去给医生检查过六七次了
Honey, we had you tested like six times.
相信我 我也宁可你真有阅读障碍
Trust me, I was praying for dyslexia.
我的天啊 你就不能让我过得开心点吗
Oh, my God, why can't you ever let me have any fun?!
老爸 太恶心了
Ew. Ew. Dad, gross.
你的手都是起司味
Your hand smells like cheese!
我不想把餐刀弄脏嘛 坐下
I didn't want to dirty a knife. Sit.
咱都知道每次迪蒂姥姥来的时候
Now, we all know when Nana Dede comes to visit,
-你们的妈都会有点... -抽风吗
- your mom can get a little... - Psycho?
-恐怖吗 -像发酒疯吗
- Scary. - Drunk?
都有
All true.
所以 我要你们都拿出最棒最乖的一面
Therefore, I need you guys to be on your best behavior.
别担心 我一向如此
Don't worry. I'll keep to myself.
我还得练习我的大提琴独奏会曲目呢
I have to practice for my cello recital.
随便你吧
Ohh, fine.
这样吧 只要能让你远离你妈的"雷区"
You know what? If it keeps you out of your mom's hair, yes,
就做吧
do that.
卢克 如果你妈要抓狂了
Luke, if your mom starts to lose it,
你一定要加倍卖萌 努力让她恢复正常
I need you to lighten the mood by being extra cute.
包我身上 我准备好了几招呢
No problem. I've got some stuff prepared.
马麻 伦家好口渴哦
"Hey, mom, I'm firsty".
不错吧 可爱不
Heh? Adorable, right?
还...还行吧
Yeah, that's... that's good.
别担心 我穿上睡衣 装可爱的效果就棒了
Don't worry. It works better in my jammies.
小卡 莫妮卡这周末来不了莉莉的生日会了
Cam, Monica can't come to Lily's birthday party this weekend.
她妈妈要来芝加哥[双关演音乐剧"芝加哥"]
Her mom's gonna be in Chicago.
太棒了 她要演啥
Oh, that's fantastic! What part is she playing?
芝加哥 地名
The city of Chicago.
好吧 假设现在有枪指着你要你选
Okay. Gun to your head...
你说哪双比较好
which pair should I wear?
拿枪逼我选啊
Oh. Gun to my head.
我选直接毙了我吧
I'd say, pull the trigger.
你这是啥意思
What's that supposed to mean?
不准演费兹波
No Fizbo.
可是 为什么不行嘛
Okay, w-why?!
小卡 莉莉的生日会焦点应该是莉莉
C-Cam, the center of attention at Lily's party should be Lily,
而不是想要众人关爱的小丑费兹波
not Fizbo the needy clown.
不好意思没听清 你说谁想要众人关爱
I'm sorry. Excuse me. "Needy"?
"他们为虾米不笑呢 米奇尔"
"Why aren't they laughing, Mitchell?
"为虾米我从嘴里拉出一条手绢来
"Why aren't they clapping
"他们也不鼓掌呢"
when I'm pulling the handkerchief out of my mouth?"
那是条十英尺长的手绢
It's 10 feet long
而且最后一节还绑了四角裤
with boxer shorts at the end.
完全没有理由不鼓掌
It works on so many levels.
好吧 但是
Yeah. Well, also,
这毕竟是"小公主"主题生日会 所以...
it's a princess theme party, so...
你根本没把派对主题放在眼里吧
I guess you just don't respect party themes.
你居然说这种话
You did not just say that.
对不起 这...这说的是有点过分
I'm sorry. That was... That was crossing a line.
非常过分
Yes, it was.
所以呢 费兹波能不能"来"生日会嘛
So? Can Fizbo come to the party?
不 没戏
No! No!
你是莉莉的爸爸 以好爸爸的身份出席就行了
You are Lily's dad. Just be there as her dad.
你是说我现在不是个好爸爸吗
Are you implying I'm not being a good dad now?
你说是就是呗...[双关"如果鞋子合脚"]
Well, if the shoe fits...
不合脚 它们都大得吓人
They don't. They're comically large.
老妈
Hey, mom.
爸爸和姥姥停好车了
Dad and nana just pulled in.
克莱尔乖乖
Claire bear!
我的小宝贝儿
Ohh. Oh, my sweet girl!
天啊 我都忘了你都长这么大了
Gosh, I forget that you're all grown up.
我总觉得你还是个12岁小姑娘似的
You know, in my mind, you're still 12.
看看咱俩...两个小老太啦
Well, look at us... just two old ladies.
我们回来啦
We're home!
回来就好
Oh, good.
我们给莉莉买了非常棒的生日礼物哦
And we bought Lily a beautiful birthday gift.
我本来一直争取买羊毛毯的
Yeah. I was pushing for a cashmere throw.
杰 我买了本有声读物
Look, Jay. It's a talking storybook.
咱们可以把声音录进去
We record ourselves reading it,
这样到了晚上
and then at night,
莉莉就能听着咱们的声音入睡了
Lily can hear our voices before she goes to sleep.
糟透了
Terrible idea.
就说还是羊绒永恒
Unlike the timelessness of cashmere.
别再叨叨羊绒了
Enough with the cashmere!
这礼物哪里糟了嘛
Why is it a terrible idea?
你不记得答录机事件了吗
Don't you remember the answering-machine message?
你好 这里是杰...
Hi, you've reached Jay...
和歌洛莉亚的家
And Gloria.
请在这之后留下讯息... "嗒"
Please leave a message after the...
你没说"哔"
You didn't say "beep".
如果我说了"哔"字
If I say "beep",
别人可能以为这就是那声"哔"
then the people will think it's the beep.
不会 他们知道该等到真正的"哔"声后的
No, I think they're gonna know to wait for the actual beep.
-我不觉得他们会知道 -听我的就对了
- I don't think they'll know. - Just trust me.
那好吧
Okay, fine.
-你好 这里是杰... -和歌洛莉亚的家
- Hi, you've reached Jay... - And Gloria.
请在"哔"声后留言
Please leave a message after the beeeeeep!
你闹啥呢
What was that?
你跟我讲要"哔"
You told me to make the beep.
我不是让你模仿"哔"声
No, I didn't tell you to make the beep.
我是让你说哔字
I told you to say the word "beep."
如果我说了哔字
If I say the word,
会让人以为那是真的"哔"声嘛
then people think it's the beep.
-那不是真的"哔"声 -那干嘛还要说那哔字
- It's not the beep! - Then why even say it?!
对了
So, anyways,
你肯定猜不到我在机场碰到谁了
you'll never guess who I saw at the airport.
谁啊
Mm. Who's that?
罗比·苏利文
Robbie Sullivan.
罗比...跟我同一个高中的罗比·苏利文吗
Robbie... my Robbie Sullivan from high school?
天啊 我有...好几年没见过他了
God, I haven't seen him in...years.
应该是"几十年"了
Decades, really.
我一直挺喜欢他的
I always liked him.
而且我还记得
And as I recall,
你们俩老是对对方毛手毛脚的
the two of you couldn't keep your hands off each other.
真的呀 老妈
Oh, really, mom?
当然是...假的
That's...not true.
是真的 你日记里写的
It is true. I read it in your diary.
你偷看我日记
You read my diary!
好吧
Well...Yeah.
我 我是读过
I-I read it
我这不想看看你嗑没嗑药嘛
because I wanted to see if you were on drugs.
这是爱的管教 克莱尔
It's called parenting, Claire.
-那 老妈 查德怎么样 -伙计
- So, mom, what's going on with Chad... - Okay, buddy.
看来你得提前上前线了
we're gonna need you on the front lines sooner than expected.
准备好卖萌了没
Are you ready to be cute?
-废话 -上吧
- Please. - Go get 'em.
妈咪 伦家的小肚肚咕噜咕噜的呢
Hi, mommy. My tummy's growling.
伦家想吃通心粉粉嘛
Can I have some pas-ghetti?
宝贝 你弄痛我了
Sweetie, you're hurting me.
还有 今晚去洗个澡吧 你头发闻起来像起司
And take a shower tonight. Your hair smells like cheese.
我来开门
I'll get it.
我要一个巨大号棒棒糖
Okay, I need a giant lollipop,
现在就要
and I need it now.
我的宝贝妞来了
Oh, there's my girl!
天啊
Oh, my God.
-罗比 -瞅瞅你
- Robbie?! - Look at you!
惊喜啊
Surprise!
我请他来吃晚饭的
I invited him to dinner!
啥
What?
我就说了她会超激动吧
Didn't I tell you she'd be excited?
我...
Huh? I... Uh-huh.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
也许来杯气泡水果鸡尾酒能让你放松一下
Well, maybe a fuzzy navel wine cooler will loosen you up.
至少以前管用
Sure used to.
亲爱的 这是哪位
Hey, honey, who's this?
这位是...
This is, um...
罗比
Robbie...
我十七岁时的男朋友
My boyfriend from when I was 17 years old,
我妈请他来吃晚饭
whom my mom invited to dinner.
准备好要来狂欢了吗[直译为"系紧安全带"]
Fasten your seatbelts.
我是菲尔·邓菲
Phil Dunphy.
菲尔 你好 你和克莱尔怎么认识的
Hey, Phil. How do you know Claire?
自打跟她结婚 我就认识她了
I know Claire from being married to Claire.
等等
Wait a minute. Uh...
我妈没跟你提我结婚了
Mom didn't mention that I'm married
-还有仨娃吗 -没有 她只说
- with three kids? - No. All she said
你还在试图找寻生命的目标
was that you were still trying to figure out your life.
-真的 -对
- Really? - Yeah.
-老妈 你怎么解释 -迪蒂
- Okay. Mom? - Dede?
-谁不是在找目标呢 -不是吧
- Aren't we all? - Uh, no. Not really.
你为什么不跟他说我结婚了
Why would you not mention that I'm married?
老天 克莱尔
Oh, God, Claire.
跟人家聊天干嘛一定得提到你
Not everything in a conversation is about you.
妈...
Mom...
...麻烦您老来厨房一趟
...I could use some help in the kitchen.
你说的哦 我可没说过
Your words, not mine.
你开加长轿车来的?
You came here in a limo?
没错 小朋友
Yep. That's right, little dude.
你很有钱吗
Are you rich?
卢克 这样问很不礼貌哦
Luke, that's not polite.
罗比没准儿没什么钱
Maybe Robbie isn't rich,
他只是需要加长轿车来逃避醉驾盘查
but he needs a limo because he has a lot of DUIs.
不 那是瞎扯
Nope. It's nothing like that.
事实上 卢克 我富得流油
The truth is, Luke, I am rich,
当然不是指金钱上
but not with money.
我有迷人的腹肌
I've got my abs,
外加一头秀发
I've got my hair,
我的工作就是开外面那辆加长轿车到处跑
and I've got a super-sweet job driving that limo outside.
-酷毙了 -是很酷
- Cool. - It is cool.
卢克 我和你爸
Hey, Luke, who's taller?
谁个儿高
Me or your dad?
我觉得咱们没必要...
Oh... I don't think we need to...
我没穿鞋哦
I am just wearing socks, buddy.
我真不能理解你把他叫来是想干嘛
I just don't understand why you invited him to my house.
他是个老朋友嘛
Because he's an old friend.
不然你想让我怎样...不鸟他吗
What was I gonna do... not invite him?
没错
Yes. Yes.
宝贝 我不知道你是啥情况
Sweetheart, I don't know about you,
但我小时候可不是这么被教育的
but that is not the way I was raised.
我是被你教育大的
You raised me.
总之是你想太多了
You're overthinking this.
我还以为见到他
I was thinking that it might be a hoot
能让你高兴呢
for you to see him again.
那你想过没 提前跟我打个招呼我会更高兴
And did you think it might be a hoot to ask me first?
没 如果我事先问你 你肯定不会答应
No. If I'd asked you, you would have said no.
废话 老妈 我当然不会答应
Of course, mom. Of course I would have said no.
所以一切都是我的错吗
Oh. And I'm the bad guy.
说真的 克莱尔
Honestly, Claire,
我真希望能把你的话录下来
I wish I had a tape recorder.
"很久很久之前 有一家小熊熊
"Once upon a time, there lived a family of bears.
"家里有熊爸爸..."
"There was papa bear"...
该你了 杰
That's you, Jay.
好吧 我看看啊
Ah. Okay. Let's see.
是不是要我到院子里举这书你才能看见啊
Do you want me to hold it and stand in the driveway?
"老天啊 这鲑鱼真不错"
"Holy mackerel, this is good salmon."
我觉得他们错过...
I feel like they missed an oppor...
"我不要吃鱼
"I don't want to eat the fish.
"它们都是我的好朋友"
They are my friends!"
你鬼哭狼嚎什么呢
What kind of voice is that?
-我在扮演熊熊 -你那是熊吗
- I am a bear. - A bear?
我差点要去拿十字架来驱魔了
I was gonna get a crucifix.
"然后小熊熊说..."
"And then the baby bear said..."
"妈咪晚安 爸爸安安
"Good night, mama. Good night, papa.
"这是我有生以来最高兴的一天"
This has been the best day ever."
"接着她跟父母分别晚安亲亲
"And after she kissed her parents good night,
"然后慢慢进入梦乡
"she drifted off to sleep.
"故事完"
"The end."
"她"吗 这是只小母熊啊
She? Baby bear's a girl?
那咱得重来一遍
We have to do it over.
小母熊可不能这么演
I would have played it totally different.
-我倒觉得你挺像的 -你啥意思
- I think you nailed it. - And what's that supposed to mean?
曼尼 没事了
Manny, you're fine.
但是 杰 我得跟你说两句
But, Jay, I need to tell you something.
我已经尽力扮演一只熊了 歌洛莉亚
It's a bear, Gloria. I did the best I could.
不 我要说的是 我不想你不开心
No. I don't want you to get upset about this,
可是我不去那生日派对了
but I'm not going to the party.
什么
What?
因为你前妻也要去
Yeah, it's because your ex-wife is going to be there,
你知道我们一直处不来
and we're never good together.
我一想这个就紧张
I'm feeling very nervous.
我还是不去了比较好
It's better that I stay here.
我...
Wow. I...
我真不知道该怎么说
I don't know what to say.
简直是特大喜讯
Greatest news ever!
你同意了是吧
So you're okay with this?
也不能说很同意吧 但我理解
Well, I wouldn't say I'm okay with it, but I get it.
其实我对去参加你朋友女儿的初次圣礼
I feel like I'm in the same boat with your friend's daughter's
也是一样的感觉
first communion coming up.
我一直觉得那女孩儿她爸不喜欢我
I always felt like the husband never liked me.
或许你是对的
Maybe you're right.
我压根儿就不该去
I should probably skip it.
等等
Wait, wait, wait.
你是说罗比·苏利文现在在你家
So Robbie Sullivan's at your house right now.
对 他正跟我家跟我家人共进晚餐呢
Yes, he is having dinner with my family.
跟你们说
And let me tell you something.
那小妞超肥的
This chick was fat.
他每张一次嘴
Every time he opens his mouth,
我就感觉我女儿对我的尊重越来越低了
I can feel my daughters losing respect for me.
其实我一直都不喜欢那家伙
You know, I never liked that guy.
他总是用手臂给我来个"锁喉"
He used to always put me in a headlock.
咱们怎么老和极品约会啊
It is amazing the freaks we used to date.
"各位盆友 乃们好啊"
'Ello, gov'nah!
我得挂了
I gotta jump.
好吧 你继续
All right. Let's hear it.
费兹波·拉特
Sir Fizbo-lot,
皇家剧团御用小丑 为您效劳
royal court Jester, at your service.
我听说这儿有位小公主
I understand there's a little princess
想乐呵乐呵
'oos in need of a jolly good time!
没戏
No!
殿下 您说过小丑
Your 'ighness said that the clown
不适合出现在公主生日会
doesn't fit the princess theme.
但是鄙人愚见...
But "me finks"...
皇家御用小丑简直太合适了
That a court Jester is right as rain!
我再也不信人家说的
There goes the theory
英国口音会让人听起来聪明些的垃圾理论了
that an English accent makes everyone sound smart.
拜托
Oh, come on.
如果一点娱乐节目都没有 生日会多无聊啊
It's gonna be a boring party without any entertainment.
这点我赞同 所以我雇了个公主
I agree, which is why I hired a princess.
惊呼开始
Cue the gasp.
你怎么能 你怎么敢
How could you do that? How dare you?!
我生来就是为了让孩子们开心的
Entertaining and delighting children is who I am.
你还是先当好家长吧
Just be a parent.
-但我很想... -给我出去
- But I want to... - Go.
-我想... -住嘴
- I want to... - Now. Stop.
我想了一下你刚才说的话
I was thinking about what you said,
我觉得我还是该去那个生日会
and maybe I should go to the party.
我说什么啦 我什么都没说啊
What'd I say? I didn't say anything.
你说的玛利亚·维多利亚初次圣礼的事
About Maria Victoria's first communion.
我们不能因为外人
We cannot let other people
而错失自己的家庭活动
make us miss important family events.
难道我不能去艾丽克斯的毕业典礼
What? I'm gonna miss Alex's graduation,
还有海莉的所有婚礼 就因为那个迪蒂吗
all of Haley's weddings, just because of Dede?
我也爱他们 他们也是我的家人
I love them. They're my family, too.
等等
Whoa, whoa. Slow down.
你都准备参加婚礼了吗
You're up to weddings already?
这么着吧
H-h-how about this?
明天先别去了
Try missing tomorrow,
看看你到底啥感觉
and then just see how that feels.
杰
Ay, Jay.
你对我真好
You're so good to me.
所以我更得去了
That's why I have to go.
我知道明天你会陪着我
You're gonna be there for me
就好像玛利亚·维多利亚初次圣礼那天
the same way I'm gonna be there for you
我也会陪着你一样
at Maria Victoria's first communion.
等等 怎么连这事都不能幸免
Wait a minute. That's back on the table?
你知道的 我们不想破坏门禁的规定
Well, you know, we didn't want to break curfew.
门禁
Curfew?!
不是吧
Oh, right.
你们俩压根就没把门禁当过一回事
As if you two ever honored a curfew.
姥姥 我喜欢你的故事 继续说
I love your stories, Nana. Keep on goin'.
你老爹以前把我吓的屁滚尿流的
Your father used to scare the crap out of me.
显然还是没成功的喝阻你 让你不再
Well, evidently not enough to keep you from sneaking in
凌晨三点溜进来
3:00 in the morning.
我都不知道是要骂你
I didn't know whether to punish you
还是帮你做个煎饼
or make you pancakes.
喂 喂 哈哈哈哈
Hey, hey! Ha ha ha ha!
晚餐吃到一半时 我跟克莱尔说
Halfway through dinner, I told Claire
无论何时她忍不住要喷她妈妈的时候
that whenever she had the urge to lash out at her mother,
她就捏我的手发泄就可以了
she should just squeeze my hand instead.
捏肿到一个医生得把我的结婚戒指切下来
A doctor had to cut off my wedding ring.
克莱尔你记得那时候我们翘课
Claire, you remember that time we cut school
-然后去码头 -恩
- and we went out to the pier... - Mm-hmm.
我们玩了那个游戏 你赢了
...And we played that game, and you won the...
-大熊猫 -大熊猫 是的
- Giant panda bear! - The panda bear... Right.
是啊是啊
Yeah. Yes.
对的
Yeah.
记得那之后我们做了什么吗
Do you remember what we did after that?
记得
Yes.
你还喜欢坐过山车吗
Hey, do you still like roller coasters?
不了
Not this one.
知道吗 虽然罗比当年是个坏孩子
You know, Robbie was a rogue,
但他就是能把你迷的袜子都掉了
but he could charm your socks off.
虽然我不太相信他会就此打住
Although I doubt he stopped there.
-哇塞 老妈 -妈
- Wow, mom. - Mom?
我们这儿都是成年人 亲爱的 几乎都是
We're all adults here, honey, pretty much.
好了 我觉得 我们吃好了
Okay, I think we're... we're done.
好吧 我还是该走了
Yeah, well, I better get going.
我明早还有活 客户是个名人
I've got an early-morning run, celebrity client.
别问我他是谁
Don't ask me who.
要是我迟到了
Let's just say that if I'm late,
我的命将会在危险边缘摇摇欲坠
I'll be in Jeopardy.
谁是艾利克斯·崔百克
Who is Alex Trebek?
是个游戏节目主持人 怎么了
Uh, he's a game-show host. Why?
没什么
No reason.
-克莱尔 -什么事
- Claire. - Yes?
这真是很棒的一餐 谢谢
This was incredible. Thanks a lot.
太棒了 这太棒了
S-so great. It was so great.
-很高兴见到你 -我知道
- So good to see you. - I know.
老朋友重新聚一聚的确是挺有意思的
Catching up was so fun.
很好
Really good.
你 你保重
Hey, you... you take good care.
-保重 -是的
- You take good care, now. - Yes.
就这样 就这样
Ohh, let's do it. Let's do that.
我送你出去
I'll walk you out.
再见
Bye!
-都是真的吗 老妈 -我那时还年轻
- Really, mom? - I was young.
我觉得他很性感
I thought he was sexy.
-回房去 -好吧
- Go to your room. - Okay.
我做到了
I did it.
她把她那些狗屁倒灶的把戏都使出来了
She brought all the crazy in her arsenal,
而我没有翻脸
and I did not crack.
我的一根手骨倒是断裂了[断裂与翻脸同字]
I think a bone in my hand did.
亲爱的 对不起 对不起
Oh, honey, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-你知道什么伤我更深吗 -什么
- You know what hurt more? - What?
我以前觉得你妈妈喜欢我的
I used to think your mother loved me.
看来 她一直都是希望你嫁给罗比
Apparently, she always wished you'd married Robbie.
不是的 亲爱的
Oh, no, sweetie.
这一切只是她想要烦我
This was all about her trying to annoy me.
算了吧 它实际上是想让你们两个结婚来着
Come on. She's practically walking you two down the aisle.
他的电话
His phone.
这些年来 我送给她的那些母亲节贺卡
All those mother's day cards I sent her...
还有那些她转给我的那些
All those joke e-mails she forwarded to me
我老早就看过的笑话邮件
months after I'd already seen them.
我以后再也不会礼貌的回你"哈哈"了 迪蒂
Well, no more polite "LOLs" for you, Dede.
不会吧 我擦
Oh! Oh! Holy cow!
好吧 好吧
Wow. Okay, well...
你是对的 不是针对我
You were right. It's not about me.
天呐
Oh, God.
你是公主
You are princess...
别盯着公主看了 你会吓到她的
Stop eyeing the princess. You're gonna freak her out.
我不知道
I don't know.
我觉得整个等待王子过来
I-I think the whole idea of needing a prince to come along
让你开心笑开怀的桥段
and make you happy,
会传达错误的信息 米奇尔
sends the wrong message, Mitchell.
我真这么觉得
I really do.
真的吗 一个成年男子
Really? And a grown man
从嘴里拉出四角裤就不会传达错误的信息吗
pulling boxer shorts out of his mouth doesn't.
我
I'm...
-你好啊 -好好好好好好
- Hey. - Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi.
你好 亲爱的
Hi. Hi, sweetie.
你好菲尔
Hey, Phil.
那么 她在哪里 妈妈在哪里
So...Where is she? Where's mom?
先来把尴尬的部分先处理掉吧
Yeah, let's get the weirdness over with.
没有啊 我以为她和你一起来呢
Oh, no. I thought she was coming with you.
没有没有
Oh, no, no.
我们自从... 那天之后就没见过他
I haven't seen mom since... let's see...
对了 是昨晚 她还和我前男友亲热了
oh, she made out with my ex-boyfriend last night.
-什么 -真的
- What? - Yeah.
不 我的天呐
No, my God!
真的 真的
Yeah. Yeah.
然后就和他一起离开了
And then she took off with him,
直到我睡着以前都没有回来
didn't come back to the house until after I was asleep,
今早又留了张可爱的小纸条
and then this morning left a cute little note
上面说 和罗比享用早餐
that said, "Having breakfast with Robbie!"
她到底在干什么 他只有她一半大
What the hell is she doing? He's half her age!
不准说
Don't say it.
我觉得这很甜蜜
I think it's sweet.
爱情是很美丽的 和年纪无关
Love is beautiful. It has no age.
当爱来的时候 就爱吧
When it's meant to be, it's meant to be.
就是这样的
That is the question.
老爸 她怎么了
Dad, what's going on over there?
你妈妈会来 让她有些紧张
She was a little nervous about your mother being here,
她吃了第一片阿普唑仑
so she tried her first Xanax,
还是用龙舌兰酒喝下去的
washed it down with a shot of tequila.
看看 那个公主 太美了
Ay, look at the princess. It's so beautiful.
是吗 我可没看出来
Really? 'Cause I don't see it.
借过
Excuse me.
这就是我们的小寿星
There's the birthday girl!
荧光粉吗
Glitter?
她会吸进肺里的
That'll settle in her lungs.
我是想问问 你想要哪一种付款方式
So, I wanted to ask what method of payment you prefer...
现金 刷卡还是支票
Cash, credit card, check?
为什么给钱 公主不需要报酬
Why, princesses don't get paid,
只需要笑声和亮晶晶的火花
except maybe in laughter and sparkles.
很可爱 但是我真想知道
That's nice. But I really need to know.
我要的只是小寿星的生日愿望
All I ask is that a little girl's birthday wishes...
实现
Come true
小姐 说真的
Miss, seriously,
你要是想得到报酬 我得有你的
if you want to get paid, I need to...
好吧 你可以用支票付给派对明星公司
Fine. You can make the check out to Party Stars Incorporated.
永远不能停演角色 绝对不行
Never break character. Never, ever!
-但是 -没有但是
- But... - "But" Nothing.
我当小丑的时候 我鞋子着火了
When I was a clown, my shoe caught on fire,
我一起的一个小丑
and one of my fellow clowns
用了易燃的彩纸桶来帮我灭火
put me out with a bucket of flammable confetti.
怎么了
What's happening?
就连他们抬我上救护车的时候
Even as they loaded me into the ambulance,
我还在吹气球折动物
I continued to make balloon animals!
易燃的彩纸吗
Flammable confetti?
当时有一瓶气泡矿泉水也没用它
There was a Seltzer bottle right there!
你好
Oh, hi!
我真不敢相信
I cannot believe it.
她把他带到派对来了
She brought him to the party!
天呐 我要去杀了她
Oh, my God! I'm gonna kill her.
-我要 -停下 别 现在别
- I'm gonna... - Stop. No, not... not now.
我最不需要的就是来个大闹剧 克莱尔
The last thing I need is some big scene, Claire.
你知道她这样做只是要折磨我
You know, she's doing this just to torture me.
不 不 她这是为了报复我
No, no. She's doing this to get back at me
因为我不想让她和我们住一起
because I didn't let her stay with us.
你们都错了 是因为我
You're both wrong. This is about me.
我娶了年轻的姑娘 她就带个小伙子
I got the young girl. She had to get the young guy.
她和我还挺好
Well, she and I are good.
我们昨晚灌完那一瓶酒
We had a long talk last night
长谈了一次
after you and I "split" that bottle of wine,
然后你在楼梯上睡着了
and you "fell asleep" on the stairs.
我不明白为什么大家对这事都很不爽
I don't know why everybody's getting so upset about this.
他们可能只是热情使然啊
Maybe it's about passion,
或是肉体的需求
about what the body wants,
或是她的心想要什么
what the... what the heart wants for the heart.
老爸 真的 你能
Dad, seriously, can you
处理一下这两麻烦人物吗
deal with Cheech and Chong?
你们好啊
Hi, everyone.
杰 歌洛莉亚
Jay, Gloria.
早上好 迪蒂
Oh, buenos dias, Dede...
你好啊 美女
B-buenos...
好了 歌洛莉亚
Uh, yeah. Uh, Gloria...
来吧
Come on.
可以了
That's enough.
老妈
Hi, mom. Hi.
米奇尔
Oh, Mitchell. Mwah!
谢谢你来出席
Thank you for coming.
你记得罗比吧
Oh! You remember Robbie.
是啊 记得 记得 你好
Yes, I do. Yes. Hi.
那是莉莉
Oh! That's Lily!
我想你们完全没试着
Oh! I guess you're trying
把我送她的衣服保持干净
to keep the outfit I sent her clean.
罗比
So, Robbie,
感觉这些年你过得不错啊
it looks like the years have been treating you good, huh?
-过的怎么样啊 小红帽 -好了
- Hey, what's up, Red? - Okay. Um...
我喜欢这家伙 记得吗 我们以前经常
I love this guy. Remember, we used to wrestle around
一起摔跤吗
all the time?
行了 快停下 我宝宝在看吗
Yeah. Please stop. Is my baby watching?
真高兴见到你 伙计
Good to see you, man.
我要跟你谈几句
I need to talk to you for a second.
让我
Let me just...
问你些事情
...ask you a little something.
你跟我妈在一起干什么
What are you doing with my mother?
我有句话
Hey, I've got a code.
"在加长轿车里发生的事 就留在车里吧"
What happens in the limo stays in the limo.
她是我妈妈
She's my mother!
听着 我知道这一切有点奇怪
Look, I know this is all a little freaky,
但是在高中时我就爱上你妈妈了
but I had a crush on your mother back in high school,
而一直以来我都在幻想这事
and it's always been kind of a fantasy for me.
你那时和我约会 还对我妈妈抱有幻想啊
You were dating me and fantasizing about my mother?
惨了
Ohh, boy.
怎么了
What?
我想我们都心知肚明你是在生气什么
I think we both know what this is really all about.
不
Uh, no.
你还是想要我的
You still want me.
天呐 你是疯了吧
Oh, my God. Are you insane?
你们两个怎么了
Oh, what's going on here, you two?
克莱尔还想要我
Claire still wants me.
不 别乱说
No. Don't.
我本应预料到这事的
Oh...Oh, I should've seen this coming.
是吗
Oh, really.
她一看见我高兴
One minute she sees I'm happy,
-她就想横刀夺爱 -我没有
- and she swoops in! - Didn't swoop!
我没有 要是真有人想横刀 那也是你
I didn't swoop. If anybody swooped, it was you!
是你横刀夺爱
You swooped!
克莱尔 别吵 现在别 现在别吵
Claire, hush. Not now! Not now!
别吵 别 停下吧 求你了
Not now. No, stop, please.
她指责我试着把我前男友从她那里偷回来
She accused me of trying to steal my old boyfriend from her.
好了 好了 那你快点
Okay, fine, but make it quick.
为什么事情牵扯到你就会很难搞
Why does everything have to be so hard with you?
你为什么就不能成为一个正常的老外婆
Why can't you just be a normal old grandma?!
你为什么 为什么来这里
Why do you... you come in here,
这对你就像是个恶心的游戏
it's some sort of sick game for you
就是一直 推 推 推 推 推别人到极限
to just push people and push people and push people
看看别人还可以容忍你多久
and see how far you can push them!
很好 看看我啊
And so fine... Look at me!
你赢了 你赢了
You win! You win!
我在公主派对上大吼大叫 老妈
I'm screaming at a princess party, mom!
-克莱尔 克莱尔 -我在大吼大叫
- Claire. Claire... - I'm screaming
在一个公主派对上
at a princess party!
克莱尔 克莱尔 克莱尔 克莱尔
Claire, Claire, Claire, Claire.
罗比
Robbie?
我觉得 你懂的 你应该走了
I think maybe, you know, you should take off.
是的是的 我听见了 菲尔
Yeah, yeah, look, I hear you, Phil.
不过我偷偷告诉你
Uh, but between you and me...
我感觉那边的那个公主
I'm getting some serious vibes
在对我放电
from the princess over here,
我想留着看看有没有戏
and I'd kind of like to play that out.
你该走了
Hey. Time to go.
普先生 你好吗
Hey, Mr. P. How you been?
我很好
I'm doing good.
我以前就不喜欢你跟我女儿在地下室鬼混
But I never liked you in the basement with my daughter,
我也不喜欢你和我前妻在这厮混
and I don't like you here with my ex.
你懂吗 你那小小的恐吓
You know, your little intimidation game
可能对我小时候有点用
may have worked on me when I was a kid,
我现在已经完全长大了...
but I'm a full-grown man now...
我觉得我是该走了
And I think I should go.
"让莉莉成为派对的主角"这事做得太好了
So much for keeping it all about Lily.
是啊 我承认我控制不住
Well, yeah, and I certainly didn't help
就跑去训斥那个很可爱的临时工公主
by berating that perfectly sweet journeyman princess like I did.
天呐 看看这里
Oh, God, look at this place.
每个人都吓坏了
Everybody's traumatized.
我们需要有人来
Oh, we need somebody to
把派对气氛再搞起来 你说是吧
pump some life back into this party, huh?
我知道了 我去屋里放些音乐
I got this. I'll go in and turn on some music,
拿出纸杯蛋糕 打开泡泡机器
bring out the cupcakes, pump up the bubble machine.
或者
Or...
你这是迂回的告诉我
Is that a roundabout way of saying
让某个小丑出现在派对上吗
a certain clown can come to the party?
我之前错了
I was wrong.
哪个孩子不想要有个小丑爸爸啊
Every kid wants a clown for a dad.
你的决定 让一个小女孩开心死了
Oh! You just made a little girl very happy.
是啊 我知道
Yes, well, I can see that.
你还好吧
You okay?
我没事
I'm fine.
我会没事的
I will be fine.
你知道克莱尔压力太大爆发后 会说气话的
'Cause you know Claire gets stressed out.
她在那里说的那些
That stuff she said out there...
都是实话
Was all true.
是啊
Yeah.
不知道我是怎么想 会和他在一起
I don't know what I was thinking with him.
我觉得像个傻子
I feel like such a fool.
你只是因为一个小伙子的注意有点飘飘然了
You got flattered by the attention of a younger guy,
所以你有点太奔放了
and you got a little carried away.
-那又怎样 -不是那样的
- So what? - It's not that.
我和你离婚
It's... I divorced you,
是因为我想追寻不一样的人事物
because I was looking for something else.
但我到现在都还没找到
I haven't found it.
但当我回来的时候
But when I come back here,
我觉得我得证明一些事情
I feel like I have to prove something.
就像人家看着我
Like people are looking at me,
说 你破坏了这个家庭
saying, "You broke up the family.
你还想表示些什么
What do you have to show for it?"
你做的对的
You did the right thing.
我们失控了
We were stalled.
我没胆去结束
I didn't have the guts to end it.
因为你是个好男人
That's because you're a decent man.
那也没让事情更简单些
And that doesn't make it any easier.
我只是不想被认为是个疯狂的姥姥
I just don't want to be thought of as "crazy nana".
那不是真的我
That's not really who I am.
我觉得 更重要的是
I think, more than anything else,
我真的问题
my real problem...
是她
is her!
什么
Huh?
不要 迪蒂 你在干什么
No, Dede!
也许 这也不是因为我
So, maybe it isn't about me?
或者我
Or me.
我跟你们说了 是因为我
I told you it was about me!
不要 不要
No! No!
我来救歌洛莉亚
I got Gloria!
这真是个珍贵的礼物
This is such a precious gift!
我知道 真不敢相信我爸爸坐下来做了这个
I know. I can't believe my dad sat down and did this.
继续
Keep going.
杰 集中注意力 到你念台词了
Jay, pay attention. It's your line!
我才刚念完一句白痴台词
I just had a damn line.
曼尼 帮我添酒
Manny, freshen this up for me.
不行 我们完成之前不能再喝酒
No, no more drinks until we finish this.
管他呢 反正小卡也会婉拒这东西
Who cares? Cam's just gonna return it anyway.
惊呼开始
Cue gasp.